Guide to the Fales Manuscript Collection circa 1700-2000 MSS.001
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Letter sized boxes
  - Whitten, Wilfred (1864-1942) (John O'London, pseud.): MS. [9pp.] Ball and Cross [see also Oversize], undated (Box 187, Folder 13)
  - Whitten, Wilfred (1864-1942) (John O'London, pseud.): MS. Charles Lamb, Londoner; 1 Letter and Envelope, undated (Box 187, Folder 14)
  - Whitten, Wilfred (1864-1942) (John O'London, pseud.): MS. Christmas with a Difference [36 pp.], undated (Box 187, Folder 15)
  - Whittier, John Greenleaf (1807-1892): 21 Letters (1825-1891); 1 Fragment [undated]; 4 Letters [undated or ?], 1825-1891; undated (Box 187, Folder 16)
  - Whyte-Melville, Charlotte (Hanbury), undated (Box 187, Folder 17a)
  - Whyte-Melville, George John (1821-1878), undated (Box 187, Folder 17b)
  - Whyte-Melville, John (d. 1883), undated (Box 187, Folder 17c)
  - Wickham, William: MS. Account Book [ca. 1609] (Box 187, Folder 18)
  - Widdener, Margaret, undated (Box 187, Folder 19a)
  - Wieners, John, undated (Box 187, Folder 19b)
  - Wieners, John: TSS. Of Asphodel, In Hell's Despite [One Act Play]; One Act Scene [later Still Life], undated (Box 187, Folder 20)
  - Wigan, Alfred, undated (Box 187, Folder 21a)
  - Wigan, H., undated (Box 187, Folder 21b)
  - Wiggin, Kate Douglas (Smith) (1856-1925), undated (Box 187, Folder 21c)
  - Wilberforce, Octavia (1888-1963): Unfinished Memoirs, undated (Box 187.5, Folder 1a)
  - Wilberforce, Octavia (1888-1963): Unfinished Memoirs, undated (Box 187.5, Folder 1b)
  - Wilberforce, Octavia (1888-1963): Unfinished Memoirs, undated (Box 187.5, Folder 1c)
  - Wilberforce, Octavia (1888-1963): Unfinished Memoirs, undated (Box 187.5, Folder 1)
  - Wilcox, Ella Wheeler (1850-1919): 6 Letters (1888-1916); 1 Fragment; MS. The Birth of the Opal; MS. Education and Morality (Box 187.5, Folder 2)
  - Wilde, Constance (Lloyd) (Mrs. Oscar Wilde), undated (Box 187.5, Folder 3a)
  - Wilde, Jane Frances (Elgee), Lady (1826-1896), undated (Box 187.5, Folder 3b)
  - Wilde, Oscar (1854-1900): 9 Letters (1882-91) [see also Oversize and Ross, Robert] (Box 187.5, Folder 4)
  - Wilde, Oscar (1854-1900): 4 Letters to Wilde; 1 Letter re Wilde in Prison, undated; 1895 (Box 187.5, Folder 5)
  - Wilde, Oscar (1854-1900): Farewell Lecture, Globe Theatre [June 2, 1882] (Box 187.5, Folder 6)
  - Wilde, Oscar (1854-1900): 1 Photograph by N. Sarony. 1 Cabinet card., 1880s (Box 187.5, Folder 6.A)
  - Wilde, William Robert Wills, Sir (1815-1876): 2 Letters, undated (Box 187.5, Folder 7)
  - Wilder, Amos N.; Wilder, Isabel, undated (Box 187.5, Folder 8)
  - [Wilder, Thornton: see also Boxes 189 & 190], 1690-2000 (Box not specified, Folder 8)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): MS. The Portrait of Thornton Wilder by Gertrude Stein (in T.W.'s hand), undated (Box 187.5, Folder 9a)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): interview in The Paris Review, undated (Box 187.5, Folder 9b)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Letter and Cards, undated (Box 187.5, Folder 10)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Our Town; Letters re Original Play, undated (Box 187.5, Folder 11)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Our Town T.S. carbon, undated (Box 187.5, Folder 12)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Our Town "The crickit", undated (Box 187.5, Folder 13)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Our Town "Property Plot", undated (Box 187.5, Folder 14)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Our Town "Costume Plot", undated (Box 187.5, Folder 15)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Our Town "Compilation of Newspaper Reviews", undated (Box 187.5, Folder 16)
  - Whitman, Walt (1819-1892): 1 Letter; 2 P.C.; 1 Envelope; 1 Letter removed from Reading Room West Wall, undated (Box 188, Folder 1)
  - Whitman, Walt (1819-1892): 1962 Report on the "Walt Whitman Building" 98 Cranberry St. (Box 188, Folder 2)
  - Whitman, Walt (1819-1892): Committee to Save the Walt Whitman Building: 21 letters Maria Lazlo, undated (Box 188, Folder 3)
  - Whitman, Walt (1819-1892): Committee to Save the Walt Whitman Building: 30 Letters from Elias Wilentz, undated (Box 188, Folder 4)
  - Whitman, Walt (1819-1892): Committee to Save the Walt Whitman Building: Letters of approval, undated (Box 188, Folder 5)
  - Whitman, Walt (1819-1892): Committee to Save the Walt Whitman Building: Letters in support [see also Marianne Moore], undated (Box 188, Folder 6)
  - Whitman, Walt (1819-1892): Committee to Save the Walt Whitman Building: 1 News Release; 3 Flyers; 1 Exerpt from Leaves...; Letterheads; 1 "Dear Friends" letter from Elias Wilentz, undated (Box 188, Folder 7)
  - Whitman, Walt (1819-1892): Committee to Save the Walt Whitman Building: Letters declining support, undated (Box 188, Folder 8)
  - Whitman, Walt (1819-1892): Committee to Save the Walt Whitman Building: Official Letters and Reports [see also Oversize], undated (Box 188, Folder 9)
  - Whitman, Walt (1819-1892): Committee to Save the Walt Whitman Building: Research Requests/Answers, undated (Box 188, Folder 10)
  - Whitman, Walt (1819-1892): Committee to Save the Walt Whitman Building: 4 Articles, undated (Box 188, Folder 11)
  - Whitman, Walt (1819-1892): Committee to Save the Walt Whitman Building: Clippings on Brooklyn Home, undated (Box 188, Folder 12)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Correspondence to Goldstone, Richard [1944] (Box 189, Folder 1)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Correspondence to Goldstone, Richard [1945] (Box 189, Folder 2)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Correspondence to Goldstone, Richard [1946] (Box 189, Folder 3)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Correspondence to Goldstone, Richard [1947] (Box 189, Folder 4)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Correspondence to Goldstone, Richard [1948] (Box 189, Folder 5)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Correspondence to Goldstone, Richard [1949] (Box 189, Folder 6)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Correspondence to Goldstone, Richard [February - August, 1950] (Box 189, Folder 7)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Correspondence to Goldstone, Richard [September - December, 1950] (Box 189, Folder 8)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Correspondence to Goldstone, Richard [1951] (Box 189, Folder 9)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Correspondence to Goldstone, Richard [1952] (Box 189, Folder 10)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Correspondence to Goldstone, Richard [1953] (Box 189, Folder 11)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Correspondence to Goldstone, Richard [1954-56] (Box 189, Folder 12)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Correspondence to Goldstone, Richard [1957] (Box 189, Folder 13)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Correspondence to Goldstone, Richard [1958-59] (Box 189, Folder 14)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Correspondence to Goldstone, Richard [1960-62] (Box 189, Folder 15)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Correspondence to Goldstone, Richard [1963-65] (Box 189, Folder 16)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Correspondence to Goldstone, Richard [1966-67] (Box 189, Folder 17)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Correspondence to Goldstone, Richard [1968] (Box 189, Folder 18)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Correspondence to Goldstone, Richard [1969-73] (Box 189, Folder 19)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Correspondence to Colefax, Sibyl [1928-29] (Box 190, Folder 1)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Correspondence to Colefax, Sibyl [1930-33] (Box 190, Folder 2)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Correspondence to Colefax, Sibyl [1934-35] (Box 190, Folder 3)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Correspondence to Colefax, Sibyl [1936] (Box 190, Folder 4)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Correspondence to Colefax, Sibyl [January - March, 1937] (Box 190, Folder 5)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Correspondence to Colefax, Sibyl [April - June, 1937] (Box 190, Folder 6)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Correspondence to Colefax, Sibyl [July - September, 1937] (Box 190, Folder 7)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Correspondence to Colefax, Sibyl [October - December, 1937] (Box 190, Folder 8)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Correspondence to Colefax, Sibyl [1938] (Box 190, Folder 9)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Correspondence to Colefax, Sibyl [July - November, 1938] (Box 190, Folder 10)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Correspondence to Colefax, Sibyl January - May, 1939] (Box 190, Folder 11)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Correspondence to Colefax, Sibyl June - December, 1939] (Box 190, Folder 12)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Correspondence to Colefax, Sibyl [January - June, 1940] (Box 190, Folder 13)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Correspondence to Colefax, Sibyl [July - December, 1940] (Box 190, Folder 14)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Correspondence to Colefax, Sibyl [1943-45] (Box 190, Folder 15)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Correspondence to Colefax, Sibyl [June - December, 1941] (Box 190, Folder 16)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Correspondence to Colefax, Sibyl [1942] (Box 190, Folder 17)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Correspondence to Colefax, Sibyl [1943-44] (Box 190, Folder 18)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Correspondence to Colefax, Sibyl [1945-46] (Box 190, Folder 19)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Correspondence to Colefax, Sibyl [1947] (Box 190, Folder 20)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Correspondence to Colefax, Sibyl [1948] (Box 190, Folder 21)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Correspondence to Colefax, Sibyl [January - February, 1949] (Box 190, Folder 22)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Correspondence to Colefax, Sibyl [March - December, 1949] (Box 190, Folder 23)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Correspondence to Colefax, Sibyl [January - May, 1950] (Box 190, Folder 24)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Correspondence to Colefax, Sibyl [June - December, 1950] (Box 190, Folder 25)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Correspondence to Colefax, Sibyl; MS. Memoires de Duc, undated (Box 190, Folder 26)
  - Wilder, Thornton (1897-1975): Correspondence to Goldstone, Richard re biography, 1965 (Box 190, Folder 27)
  - Wilkie, David, Sir (1785-1841), undated (Box 191, Folder 1a)
  - Williams, Helen (1762-1827), undated (Box 191, Folder 1b)
  - Williams, John Hargreaves Harley (1901- ), undated (Box 191, Folder 2a)
  - [Williams, Jonathan: see Box 192], 1690-2000 (Box not specified, Folder data_value_missing_a7f14de051a23b030a93b26b954dbf8d)
  - Williams, Thomas, undated (Box 191, Folder 2b)
  - Williams, Thomas J., undated (Box 191, Folder 2c)
  - Williams, Sherley Anne, undated (Box 191, Folder 2)
  - Williams, William Carlos (1883-1963): 6 T.L.s, poems [signed], 2 letters, and 4 photocopies, undated (Box 191, Folder 3)
  - Williams, William Carlos (1883-1963): A Novelette, undated (Box 191, Folder 4)
  - Williamson, Alice Muriel (Livingston) (1867-1933), undated (Box 191, Folder 5a)
  - Willingham, Calder, undated (Box 191, Folder 5b)
  - Willis, Nathanial Parker, undated (Box 191, Folder 6)
  - Wills, William Henry (1810-1880), undated (Box 191, Folder 7a)
  - Wilson, Colin (1931- ), undated (Box 191, Folder 7b)
  - Wilson, Desemea (Newman) (Diane Patrick, pseud.), undated (Box 191, Folder 8a)
  - Wilson, Edmond (1895- ), undated (Box 191, Folder 8b)
  - Wilson, Elena (Mrs. Edmund), undated (Box 191, Folder 8c)
  - Wilson, Harry Leon (1867-1939), undated (Box 191, Folder 8)
  - Wilson, James Grant (1832-1914), undated (Box 191, Folder 9a)
  - Wilson, John (1785-1854) (Christopher North, pseud.), undated (Box 191, Folder 9b)
  - Wilson, John (1800-1849), undated (Box 191, Folder 9c)
  - Wilson, William ("Doubleyou") (1801-1860): Such is Life; 4 Letters to Wilson; 1 Envelope; 1 Scrapbook with 5 Letters to Wilson, undated (Box 191, Folder 10)
  - Wingfeld, H.: 1 Letter (Sir Edwin Arnold [1896]) (Box 191, Folder 11)
  - Winter, William (1836-1917): 2 Letters, 1 Envelope, 1 Christmas Card, 1915 (Box 191, Folder 12)
  - Winthrop, Theodore: 1 Signature, undated (Box 191, Folder 13)
  - [Wise, Leonard: Dumachas: see Box 191.5.A], 1690-2000 (Box not specified, Folder data_value_missing_900f97974af43fb579e9e4e6164abbbc)
  - Wiseman, Nicholas Patrick Stephen, Cardinal (1802-1865): 3 Letters; 1 Invoice [funeral]; 2 Envelope, 1863, 1864 (Box 191, Folder 14)
  - Wister, Owen (1860-1938): 3 Letters [1910, 1931; undated]; 1 Note [December 7, 1928]; 1 Poem; 1 Appreciation (Box 191, Folder 15)
  - Wodehouse, P. G. (Pelham Grenville) (1881-1975): 1 Letter; 1 Note; 1 Envelope, undated (Box 191, Folder 16)
  - Wolcot, John (1738-1819) (Peter Pindar, pseud.): 1 Letter, undated (Box 191, Folder 17)
  - Wolfe, Humbert (1885-1940): 3 Letters; 1 Envelope; 1 MS. H. G. Wells; 1 MS. Arnold Bennett, undated (Box 191, Folder 18)
  - [Wolfe, Thomas: see Box 193], 1690-2000 (Box not specified, Folder data_value_missing_bd46485903995c61481e314de5b657aa)
  - Woltman, William J., undated (Box 191, Folder 19a)
  - Wood, Arthur, undated (Box 191, Folder 19b)
  - Wood, Clement (1888-1950): 6 Letters, undated (Box 191, Folder 20)
  - Wood, Mrs. Henry (nee´ Ellen Price) (1814-1887): 1 drawing, 7 letters, undated (Box 191, Folder 21)
  - Wood, Leonard, Gen. (1860-1927), undated (Box 191, Folder 22a)
  - Woodberry, George Edward (1855-1930), undated (Box 191, Folder 22b)
  - Woodhouse, Alexander Fraser Tytler, Lord (1747-1813), undated (Box 191, Folder 23a)
  - Woolf, Leonard (1880-19--), undated (Box 191, Folder 23b)
  - Woollcott, Alexander (1887-1943): 3 Letters [letter from December 17, 1940 also signed by Hemingway, Martha Gellhorn; Roosevelt, Eleanor], undated; 1940 (Box 191, Folder 24)
  - Woolsey, Sarah Chauncy (1835-1905) (Susan Coolidge, pseud.): 2 Letters, undated (Box 191, Folder 25)
  - Wordsworth, William (1770-1850): 2 Letters, undated (Box 191, Folder 26)
  - Wren, Percival Christopher (1885-1941): 1 Photograph; 1 Book Jacket, undated (Box 191, Folder 27)
  - Wright, Harold Bell (1872-1944): 1 Letter [August 24, 1933] (Box 191, Folder 28)
  - Wright, James, undated (Box 191, Folder 29a)
  - Wright, William Aldis (1831-1914), undated (Box 191, Folder 29b)
  - Wright, Willard Huntington (1888-1939) (S.S. van Dine, pseud.), undated (Box 191, Folder 29c)
  - Wylie, Elinor: 1 typed MS.; 1 auto. MS., undated (Box 191, Folder 30)
  - Yates, Edmund Hodgson (1831-1894): Letters; 1 Note; 1 Signature; 1 Bookplate, 1870-1893 (Box 191, Folder 31)
  - Yates, Margaret Tayler (1887- ): 2 Letters, 1939, 1941 (Box 191, Folder 32)
  - Yea, Rhen: 1 Letter; 1 Envelope, undated (Box 191, Folder 33)
  - Yeats, John Butler (1839-1922): 1 Letter; 1 Envelope, 1894 (Box 191, Folder 34)
  - Yeats, William Butler: (1) 8 pieces [see also Robins Papers], undated (Box 191, Folder 35)
  - Yeats, William Butler: (2), undated (Box 191, Folder 36)
  - Yeats, William Butler: (3) copies, undated (Box 191, Folder 37)
  - Yendi, Ade´laide Kemble: 1 Letter, undated (Box 191, Folder 38)
  - Yonge, Charlotte Mary (1823-1901): Letters, 1855-1876 (Box 191.5, Folder 1a)
  - Yonge, Charlotte Mary (1823-1901): 2 A.L.s[removed from The Pillars of the House; or, Under Wode, Never Rode], undated (Box 191.5, Folder 1b)
  - Yonge, Charlotte Mary (1823-1901): Letters [ca. 1876-1880] (Box 191.5, Folder 2)
  - Yonge, Charlotte Mary (1823-1901): Letters, 1880-ca. 1890 (Box 191.5, Folder 3)
  - Yonge, Charlotte Mary (1823-1901): Letters, ca. 1890-1897 (Box 191.5, Folder 4)
  - Young, Andrew (1885- ): Letter, 1859 (Box 191.5, Folder 5)
  - Young, Charles Mayne (1777-1856): 3 Letters [2 undated; 1 1833], undated; 1833 (Box 191.5, Folder 6)
  - Young, Ella (1867-1956): 2 Letters, 1945-1946 (Box 191.5, Folder 7)
  - Young, F. E. Mills (Florence Ethel Mills) (1875- ): [see also Legal Size], 1919 (Box 191.5, Folder 8)
  - Young, S. Hall: 1 Letter [January 3, 1916] (Box 191.5, Folder 9a)
  - Young, Stark, undated (Box 191.5, Folder 9b)
  - Younghusband, George: 1 Photograph; 2 Letters to Fairar, Frederick, Esq., 1929-1930 (Box 191.5, Folder 10)
  - Zaidenberg, Arthur (1903- ), undated (Box 191.5, Folder 11a)
  - Zahn, Guglielmo, undated (Box 191.5, Folder 11b)
  - Zangwill, Israel (1865-1926): Letters, 1892-1895 (Box 191.5, Folder 12)
  - Zangwill, Israel (1865-1926): Letters, 1895-1925 (Box 191.5, Folder 13)
  - Zucca, Mana (1894- ): 1 Letter, undated (Box 191.5, Folder 14)
  - Wise, Leonard: [Bound MS.] Dumachas, 1690-2000 (Box 191.5.A, Folder data_value_missing_b40d77b5a2341e2bb82cb0e99644ead2)
  - Williams, Jonathan: Correspondence with Fales Library re the Collection: 3 Letters; 1 Carbon Copy of reply [see also Oversize & Proofs], undated (Box 192, Folder 1)
  - Williams, Jonathan: 1 Memo [Oldenberg, Charles - June 5, 1968]; 2 Letters ["Eli"]; "Last Words" of Famous People (Box 192, Folder 2)
  - Williams, Jonathan: TS. corrected for Emblems for the Little Dells, and Nooks, and Corners of Paradise: 8 pp [see proofs], 1 copy of drawing, undated (Box 192, Folder 3)
  - Williams, Jonathan: Granta [January 19, 1963] [includes Emblems for Little Dells, and Nooks, and Corners of Paradise] (Box 192, Folder 4)
  - Williams, Jonathan: TS. Mahler 10 Symphonies [corrected; 42 pp.] [see also Proofs], undated (Box 192, Folder 9)
  - Williams, Jonathan: Plastic Hydrangea People Poems [preliminary worksheets, version 1, 16 pp.], undated (Box 192, Folder 5)
  - Williams, Jonathan: Plastic Hydrangea People Poems [preliminary worksheets, version 2, 10 pp.], undated (Box 192, Folder 6)
  - Williams, Jonathan: TS. Plastic Hydrangea People Poems [with glosses by Tilson, Joe; 22 pp., 1969] (Box 192, Folder 7)
  - Williams, Jonathan: Mahler 10 Symphonies [handwritten outline of each; 41 pp.] [see also corrected Proofs], undated (Box 192, Folder 8)
  - Williams, Jonathan: Final TS. Mahler [cover sheet; pp. numbered 55-96] [see also corrected Proofs], undated (Box 192, Folder 10)
  - Williams, Jonathan: Miscellaneous quotations - some from Mahler [3 pp.], undated (Box 192, Folder 11)
  - Wolfe, Thomas (1900-1938), undated (Box 193, Folder 1)
  - Wolfe, Thomas (1900-1938): To Cargill, undated (Box 193, Folder 2)
  - Wolfe, Thomas (1900-1938), undated (Box 193, Folder 3)
  - Wolfe, Thomas (1900-1938): To Watt, Homer A. [Correspondence 1924-1930; undated]; to Chase, Harry Woodburn [Correspondence, October 30, 1935], 1924-1935; undated (Box 193, Folder 4)
  - Wolfe, Thomas (1900-1938), undated (Box 193, Folder 5)
  - Wolfe, Thomas (1900-1938), undated (Box 193, Folder 6)
  - Wolfe, Thomas (1900-1938), undated (Box 193, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Unidentified, undated (Box 194, Folder 1)